<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>diversity and inclusion on ryan straight</title>
    <link>https://ryanstraight.com/tags/diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in diversity and inclusion on ryan straight</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 09:00:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ryanstraight.com/tags/diversity-and-inclusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Perspective on Diversity and Inclusion Speaker Series: Faculty Fellows</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/talk/perspective-on-diversity-and-inclusion-speaker-series-faculty-fellows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 09:00:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/talk/perspective-on-diversity-and-inclusion-speaker-series-faculty-fellows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Established in 1984, the Faculty Fellows consists of 60 exceptional faculty members who bring the feel of a small liberal arts college to a large, Research I university. With backgrounds ranging from Aerospace &amp;amp; Mechanical Engineering to Gender &amp;amp; Women’s Studies, there is one thing that all Faculty Fellows have in common – an unwavering commitment to student success. Each fellow is assigned to one of 44 sites on campus including residence halls, cultural centers, and Arizona Athletics. Spending dedicated time at their site each week provides students with an opportunity to build relationships with faculty outside of the classroom, breaking down traditional barriers and encouraging feelings of mattering and belonging. In this presentation, the Coordinator of Faculty Programs will recruit faculty fellows from across campus to speak about their experiences in the program, how the Fellows program benefits both students and faculty, and next steps for the program and creating a diverse and inclusive campus community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
