<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>squad goals network on ryan straight</title>
    <link>/tags/squad-goals-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in squad goals network on ryan straight</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 11:25:53 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/squad-goals-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching and Cooking</title>
      <link>/2019/06/01/teaching-and-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 11:25:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/01/teaching-and-cooking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching &lt;em&gt;MasterChef Junior&lt;/em&gt; got me thinking about the similarities between cooking and teaching. It&amp;rsquo;s a phenomenal show, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mise en place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus on technique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ability to improvise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quality resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attention to detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October Squad Ghouls Network Take-Over: Postmortem</title>
      <link>/2018/11/01/october-squad-ghouls-network-take-over-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 08:10:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/01/october-squad-ghouls-network-take-over-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as scary as I thought it would be. It was also quieter than I&amp;rsquo;d expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the month of October I was tasked with running the social media for the Squad Goals Network, a collective of pure academic and collaborative brilliance, of which I am honored to be a part. And you know what? I had a pretty good time. That said, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic theme for the month was &lt;em&gt;fear&lt;/em&gt;. Partly because it encompassed Halloween and partly because I believe doing things that scare you is an integral part of growing as a fully-realized person. Speaking of which, over the month I came to realize a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;revelation-1-anticipation-is-always-scarier-than-immersion&#34;&gt;Revelation #1: Anticipation is always scarier than immersion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about something is always going to be more terrifying than actually being in the situation. I kept thinking, &amp;ldquo;Is it going to be good enough?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Will I make a fool of myself?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;What if I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to say?&amp;rdquo; Upon reflection, that last one was never a real concern; the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; concern was &amp;ldquo;What if I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; to say?&amp;rdquo; But here&amp;rsquo;s the point: there was never any expectation that the things I posted or wrote would all need to be meticulously crafted, thoughtful, brilliant nuggets of wisdom. If you spend all your time crafting you never actually produce anything, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;revelation-2-i-m-an-amplifier-not-a-bullhorn&#34;&gt;Revelation #2: I&amp;rsquo;m an amplifier, not a bullhorn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some people&amp;mdash;my takeover predecessor Angela and successor Terry, just to name two&amp;mdash;who are fantastic at creating and shouting amazing things. They make connections with new people incredibly easily and actively seek out those connections. I, on the other hand, found myself being more of an amplifier for other people. In terms of Twitter, it manifested in many, many retweets but very few unique, composed tweets. There&amp;rsquo;s no right or wrong way to do this, of course. Each person has their own style and priorities. Still, if I had to choose which I find more useful&amp;hellip; it isn&amp;rsquo;t my version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;revelation-3-a-month-is-no-time-at-all&#34;&gt;Revelation #3: A month is &lt;strong&gt;no time at all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, wow, did that go quickly. Though it&amp;rsquo;s probably compounded by my birthday being at the end of October and I was eager to have that over and done with. (Thirty seven is such a low-priority age, I feel.) Now that it&amp;rsquo;s November and I can get back into my regular routine it&amp;rsquo;s suddenly conference season and the holidays. There&amp;rsquo;s never enough time for &lt;em&gt;any of it&lt;/em&gt;. Life, I mean. Never.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thank you for putting up with me behind the wheel for a month. I&amp;rsquo;ll still be amplifying the voices of brilliance I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by in this group and expect those that come after me to do even better (which, to be honest, ain&amp;rsquo;t hard).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: The Harshest Mirror</title>
      <link>/2018/10/16/9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 08:10:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/16/9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost Halloween. Let&amp;rsquo;s do something scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection is hard. It can be scary. Not for lack of content but for the what it means to potentially confront your shortcomings. Yes, the goal is to improve but to do that you must admit where you are lacking. Of course, we can couch this in platitudes like, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; at it, just that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s an area for growth.&amp;rdquo; And this is most likely true. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the fact that you still have to admit that first part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I think, is fairly typical in higher education, especially for faculty whose entire &lt;em&gt;raison d&amp;rsquo;être&lt;/em&gt; is centered around expertise. It can feel like admitting one needs improvement can be to admit one has failed in some capacity. We all make mistakes, no doubt. We all have more to learn, of course. But it&amp;rsquo;s easier to do that in solitude, safer to make self-reflections private and not do what feels like laying bare your faults and shortcomings in public. Perhaps we all want to be the duck, legs paddling frantically under the water, but looking calm and collected on the surface. I know I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written on imposter syndrome and becoming (or at least playing at being) a public intellectual and thinker. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it comes easily and naturally to most people. For those for whom it does, it seems so &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt;. They seem fearless and display the bright colors of poisonous animals that tells you, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m making myself vunerable to help others; attack at your own peril because you will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; like the outcome.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s something to which to aspire, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I &lt;strong&gt;wish&lt;/strong&gt; I had that sort of strength and fearlessness. As it happens&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t. At least, not yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to be able to say, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; when a student asked a really fantastic or insightful question that I felt like I &lt;em&gt;should&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/em&gt; been able to answer. Perhaps I did know the answer but couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall it at the moment. Perhaps I understood the questions wrong. Perhaps it was just something I flat-out did not know. Of course, we all do the redirect and say something like, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a great question. How about we all do some research and see what we come up with?&amp;rdquo; That is the goal, after all: to get learners to become self-directed. Still, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a great question&amp;rdquo; is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the same as specifically saying, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m still somewhat afraid of that. Remember, there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between being simply ignorant of something and being unprepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is precisely why I chose &amp;ldquo;fear&amp;rdquo; as my SGN topic for the month and why I want to talk about it today: my goal is to overcome that particular fear this year. This month, if I can. Forget the New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution; we need the Halloween Overcoming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: An Introduction and a Plan</title>
      <link>/2018/10/02/9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 07:42:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/02/9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to join yet another challenge: the &lt;strong&gt;9x9x25 Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;. So, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start off with, let me say that I volunteered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://squadgoalsnetwork.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#SquadGoalsNetwork&lt;/a&gt; for this challenge and take full responsibility for it. That said, I&amp;rsquo;m looking for the entire squad to do the challenge in total, not for each member to do their own 9x9x25 challenge. They can if they want but it&amp;rsquo;s far from necessary. I&amp;rsquo;m hard but I&amp;rsquo;m not cruel, sheesh. The SGN is (and continues to grow into) a collection of incredibly talented and reflective people, so the content produced should be impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s look at what the &lt;strong&gt;9x9x25 Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; is. I was introduced to it via Twitter by our own &lt;a href=&#34;http://squadgoalsnetwork.com/2018/09/19/meet-the-authors-terry-greene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Terry Green&lt;/a&gt;. The challenge is &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://extend-domains.ecampusontario.ca/the-9x9x25-challenge-more-but-not-all-the-details/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;to write about your teaching in 9 posts, over 9 weeks, with a minimum of 25 sentences per post&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first reflection, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth talking a bit about the details of my position: I teach entirely online at both the undergraduate and graduate levels at a very large Research-1 institution, and, while I&amp;rsquo;m at a giant R1, I&amp;rsquo;m what&amp;rsquo;s considered &amp;ldquo;career-track&amp;rdquo; faculty, which is to say I&amp;rsquo;m not tenure-track. My contract consists entirely of teaching and service requirements with no research expected (though, obviously, I still do it, which is the topic for another day). My normal schedule is 80% teaching (so 4 classes per semester, each counting as 20% of my time) and 20% service. This is pretty standard at our institution for career-track faculty, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching entirely online&amp;mdash;and I mean entirely, not just hybrid or having an online section; the entire program is constructed and billed as being online&amp;mdash;makes for an interesting cocktail of convenience, agility, and distance, for both good and bad. We can collaborate in our pajamas, we can make changes and implement them at moment&amp;rsquo;s notice, and reach students that couldn&amp;rsquo;t physically reach us otherwise. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty phenomenal in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can get lonely, though. I go to great pains to build community with my students, within the program, and interdisciplinarily across the college and campus, but at the end of the day I&amp;rsquo;m still sitting in my home office, hitting keys to communicate. Sure, video conferencing has gotten considerably better over the past few years but, just as there&amp;rsquo;s an experiential difference between paper books and ebooks, it&amp;rsquo;s just not the same as sitting down in physical proximity with someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s this distance that actually caused me to accept the invitation to teach an Honors class on main campus every spring semester. But, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that reflection topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of the 9x9x25 challenge is, in part, to encourage us to be more thoughtful and reflective about our teaching practices. The hope I have is that I will really begin focusing on this next week as that&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;new semester&amp;rdquo; for us (a second 7.5-week session within a larger fall semester) and I can begin with a new class experience. I have a TA (kind of, we call it something different and there are other requirements but it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just say &amp;ldquo;TA&amp;rdquo;) and am looking forward to reflecting on how I orchestrate the inclusion of her knowledge and talent into the class. The class that&amp;rsquo;s beginning is hands-down my most popular class, which makes it &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; easier to be positive about reflections. (When students are excited and happy by default it leaves you with more energy to make improvements rather than feeling like you need to put out fires.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to reading others&amp;rsquo; reflections as the challenge progresses!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2018 SGN Social Media Takeover</title>
      <link>/2018/10/01/october-2018-sgn-social-media-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 09:51:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/01/october-2018-sgn-social-media-takeover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m taking over the social media accounts for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://squadgoalsnetwork.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Squad Goals Network&lt;/a&gt; this month and it&amp;rsquo;s gonna get &lt;em&gt;spooky&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, I wanted to share a little bit about the concept, the process, the expectations, and the theme of the month. The sheer organization, thoughtfulness, and inclusion of last month&amp;rsquo;s takeover by &lt;a href=&#34;http://angelagunder.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angela Gunder&lt;/a&gt; means there are some pretty high standards for this month. That was in part the reason for this month&amp;rsquo;s theme: &lt;strong&gt;fear&lt;/strong&gt;. Fun theme, right? Right? I mean, I&amp;rsquo;ve even got one of the &lt;em&gt;Silent Hill&lt;/em&gt; game soundtracks on while I write this. I&amp;rsquo;m 100% committed to this theme, I&amp;rsquo;m tellin&amp;rsquo; ya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why fear? Simple: we all experience it and we best overcome it with help from our support systems, and what is a network like SGN at its core if not a support system? We share thoughts to clarify them, we collaborate to produce ideas and results that we never could&amp;rsquo;ve achieved on our own (synergy, basically, but that word has been robbed of all impact over the years, I think), and we quite literally just ask each other for help sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;m so glad to have been included in this network of brilliance (constellation, remember?) is that I&amp;rsquo;m usually pretty bad about connecting with people. I&amp;rsquo;m terrible with names, I&amp;rsquo;ll fall off the face of the planet for weeks or months at a time as I obsess with something new, and my memory is almost completely overrun with random facts in place of useful things like details about the people in my life. A group like SGN goes a long way to helping me either deal with, remedy, or overcome those shortfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of overcoming fear is admitting one&amp;rsquo;s shortcomings to begin with. While I often think of and paint myself as a non-standard kind of academic (hence &lt;em&gt;The New Professor&lt;/em&gt;, my podcast), I recognize that I&amp;rsquo;m far from perfect and have many, many realms of improvement I can (and should) venture into. For some, like myself, even admitting that can be scary. It&amp;rsquo;s not like it&amp;rsquo;s a secret; nobody&amp;rsquo;s perfect. It&amp;rsquo;s about acknowledging that imperfect as areas for growth, not permanent and irreparable flaws. I sometimes feel we think of ourselves as marble statues, hoping to put on display the most perfect version of ourselves: polished, impressive, towering. Then when we make mistakes or simply fail at something, that patina of perfection is marred in some way that we just know someone is going to notice and it will permanently alter and diminish the persona we&amp;rsquo;ve so carefully sculpted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I get older and learn more and more than I know less and less about the world, it occurs to me that we&amp;rsquo;re not made of marble at all. We&amp;rsquo;re simply clay. We can be remolded and repaired, improved on and changed. This also makes us vulnerable as the wrong person can come along and take a chunk out of you. That&amp;rsquo;s where having a network, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a personal learning network or a support network comes in (though, as I said, I&amp;rsquo;d venture to say they&amp;rsquo;re often one and the same): not only do your friends and family and colleagues help you repair that damage, whatever it may be, but they help you become a better version of yourself. And that&amp;rsquo;s what we should all be striving for, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s what this month is all about, for me, at least: acknowledging our fears, admitting we all make mistakes and sometimes fail despite our best efforts, and understanding that &lt;em&gt;that&amp;rsquo;s okay&lt;/em&gt;. When students tell me they&amp;rsquo;re anxious about a defense, for example, I always say the same thing: that means you care. Fear can be a great motivator if you let it be, if you can accept it as a hurdle to overcome rather than a door being shut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, I&amp;rsquo;d like you to share with me and the rest of the squad what you&amp;rsquo;re afraid of and, if we can, we can work on it together. Also, I make absolutely no apologies for the massive number of Halloween puns and jokes that I&amp;rsquo;ll be making this month. I&amp;rsquo;m a Halloween baby and it&amp;rsquo;s creeped into the very fabric of my being. So, join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sqdglsntwrk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Squad Ghouls Network&lt;/a&gt; (see?) for a month of acknowledging, admitting, and overcoming your fears.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence</title>
      <link>/2018/08/24/evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 09:48:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/24/evidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start placing the &lt;em&gt;Read&lt;/em&gt; portion of the &lt;a href=&#34;/project/read-watch-woof/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read, Watch, Woof&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; newsletters in the blog. So, while you can get the writing part of it, you&amp;rsquo;ll miss the dogs and the video if you&amp;rsquo;re not signed up. Jus&amp;rsquo; sayin&amp;rsquo;. So here&amp;rsquo;s a piece about evidence and being willing to change your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the first week of fall semester and there is &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; going on, as you can imagine. I know some of you dear readers are in the same academic boat as I am, so know that &lt;em&gt;you are seen&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about &lt;strong&gt;evidence&lt;/strong&gt;. Not evidence in the Forensic Files sense (side note: have you noticed that a television channel called &lt;em&gt;Escape&lt;/em&gt; shows almost 24-7 &amp;ldquo;true crime&amp;rdquo; shows? what on earth does that say about us?) but in the how-we-make-the-best-decisions-in-an-attempt-to-live-our-best-lives sense. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s actually about living our &lt;em&gt;longest&lt;/em&gt; lives. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain. (And add a caveat that I am &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; an expert in nutrition; just somebody who really likes bacon but also really likes bread dipped in olive oil, which explains my weakness for Carbonara.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-talk-about-carbohydrates&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about carbohydrates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago-ish, I wrote a bit about going &amp;ldquo;low-carb.&amp;rdquo; Since then, a study was released that is the largest of its sort ever published. It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect by any means (no study ever is and if anyone claims otherwise they&amp;rsquo;re trying to sell you something) but the results seem to support (pro-tip when talking about research: be wary of using absolutes like &amp;ldquo;confirm&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;prove&amp;rdquo;) the notion of All Things in Moderation. Turns out, according to the study, that going low-carb can actually shave years off your life. Turns out, the best diet is one that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;balanced&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;spread out&lt;/em&gt;, meaning doesn&amp;rsquo;t eschew one macronutrient entirely for another and actively seeks out variety. They say the ideal percentage of carbohydrates is about 50-55%. Should probably aim for the same protein-to-lean-mass ratio as usual, and then supplement with fat to reach your caloric goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems the &amp;ldquo;Eat food, not too much, mostly plants&amp;rdquo; adage isn&amp;rsquo;t far off. Does that mean everybody needs to go vegan? Of course not. But it really does suggest something closer to the Mediterranean diet is pretty ideal. At least now I have an excuse to buy that insanely expensive bottle of olive oil!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while I stand by my assertion that you should do what works for you, specifically, in concert with advice from your physician, this is simply more information that you can use to make an informed decision (along with your doctor).  See? Evidence. That&amp;rsquo;s the nature of being a skeptic and trusting in the scientific method: when new evidence that is gathered genuinely and presented with fidelity and neutrality goes against previous evidence (or, in many cases, assumptions), it&amp;rsquo;s important to incorporate that into your decision making without prejudice or embarrassment. Evidenced-based &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; is more likely to be beneficial than choices made based on whims or spurious assertions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;growth-and-i-m-not-just-talking-about-my-waistline-stupid-carbs&#34;&gt;Growth, and I&amp;rsquo;m not just talking about my waistline (&amp;hellip;stupid carbs)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to evidence more broadly. I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in evidence-based policies, decisions, anything, really. Having said that, it is in our nature to conflate and incorporate our ideas, likes, and decisions (regardless of their premises) with our senses of &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt;. Ever gotten in an argument with someone about a band that they think is just &lt;em&gt;a-ma-zing&lt;/em&gt; and you simply don&amp;rsquo;t see it? And they take it personally? Your dislike of their favorite thing is converted into a dislike of &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;. This is something I&amp;rsquo;m certain we&amp;rsquo;ve all experienced on both sides. (I will argue all night about whether &lt;em&gt;Dark Side of the Moon&lt;/em&gt; is the most perfect album of all time. Spoiler: it absolutely is.) This kind of internalization can be hugely damaging to both a healthy sense of identity and rational public discourse. I&amp;rsquo;ll simply point you toward any Facebook comment thread that devolves into a shouting match and personal insults because of something even remotely resembling a political stance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to overcome this. We need to be better at separating our opinions from our identities. We need to learn again how to grow, admit past mistakes, and see an update to our thinking upon the presentation of new evidence as a &lt;em&gt;virtue&lt;/em&gt; rather than an admittance of fault. We are works-in-progress and should be thrilled when we get to make that progress, regardless of how it happens. In a video game, if you improve your character based on something you learn in-game or a mechanic you start understanding better, do you project embarrassment onto the character because they hadn&amp;rsquo;t been doing that all along? Would it even make sense to reject that new knowledge simply because it conflicts with an existing view? No. That would be lunacy. A self-imposed handicap, hamstringing yourself for the sake of pride. So why would we do that in reality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it much more human to update your convictions and expand your thinking on a topic when presented with new information than to dig your heels in and resist simply because it means disagreeing with your past self. In politics, a change in position is often referred to as flip-flopping, but this is entirely different. If your position is that penguins live solely in the Great Lakes region of North America and, upon being presented with evidence that no, in fact, they&amp;rsquo;re from the southern hemisphere and do not actually spend any time with polar bears, you change your position about penguin habitat locations&amp;hellip; that is not flip-flopping. That&amp;rsquo;s correcting a faulty assumption. We need more of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidence gathered genuinely and presented without ulterior motive should not be seen as a threat or a personal attack on someone that held contradictory views. It should be accepted, reviewed, scrutinized, and incorporated in an existing body of evidence and used to make better, more informed decisions about our lives and the world at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a long way of saying I&amp;rsquo;m eating bread again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hang Out With Me After Class</title>
      <link>/2017/04/26/hang-out-with-me-after-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 16:58:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/26/hang-out-with-me-after-class/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I teach fully online. Not hybrid or via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lifesize.com/en/video-conferencing-cameras&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ITV&lt;/a&gt; in an actual classroom, but 100% virtually from my home office. Only on rare occasions do I get the pleasure of physically meeting my students. Even then, that&amp;rsquo;s typically at graduation and there&amp;rsquo;s precious little time to spend with them at such an event. They, rightfully so, should be with their loved ones, basking in the glory of that achievement, not hanging out with their nerdy professor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching online is wonderful. It provides this neophile an opportunity to play with new technologies and delivery methods otherwise unavailable. It lets me meet, teach, and learn from students so geographically distant that I never would have otherwise. It affords students the temporal freedom of self-pacing (most of the time) and me the freedom to grade in my pajamas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said all that, online education within a traditional university, as opposed to entities like Khan Academy, can be problematic. The spark for this was a tweet (since deleted) with this gif and the text, &amp;ldquo;When no students show up to your seminar&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/dTfECToEK59M4/source.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia. (Not for Pulp Fiction, though I really should rewatch it soon.) It occurred to me that this represents something that I miss about traditional face-to-face classes, though not directly. (Incidentally, I&amp;rsquo;m not generally anxious but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen conference talks and symposia suffering from similar attendance and just thinking about it is discomforting. Awk-ward.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never &amp;ldquo;meet&amp;rdquo; face-to-face for class though we do have frequent video meetings (my classes are relatively small) so there&amp;rsquo;s never a chance for us to hang out afterward or meet for lunch beforehand. We&amp;rsquo;re all over the world so going to a brown-bag or symposium like the one jokingly referenced to in the tweet isn&amp;rsquo;t an option (unless it&amp;rsquo;s a webinar, I suppose). Students don&amp;rsquo;t have the option to stay behind after class dismisses and chat with me about class and life (which was always one of my favorite parts of the college experience; maybe I was &amp;ldquo;that student,&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t know). Initially this was self-imposed as we were designed but not required to be fully online. Now we&amp;rsquo;re included in &lt;a href=&#34;http://uaonline.arizona.edu/program/educational-technology-ms&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a fully online campus&lt;/a&gt; that by design provides no face-to-face physical meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say an online program or class can&amp;rsquo;t be social. Far from it. There&amp;rsquo;s even &lt;a href=&#34;https://coi.athabascau.ca/coi-model/description-social-presence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a framework for course design and implementation that has the social aspect built right in (CoI)&lt;/a&gt;. Behavior and thoughtful decision can improve the social experience for students in online environments and certainly has been proven as such. It&amp;rsquo;s still not the same. Nor is it supposed to be. These are different modalities with different expectations and affordances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my experience, two things mainly happen when students are on the other side of a computer rather than a desk and aren&amp;rsquo;t fully comfortable being &amp;lsquo;digital,&amp;rsquo; as it were: they either clam up and become incredibly passive or they can go overboard with the &amp;lsquo;bravery of being out of range.&amp;rsquo; (No, not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; Bravery of Being Out of Range, but let&amp;rsquo;s listen, anyway.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:HAHAHUGOSHORTCOD&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:HAHAHUGOSHORTCOD&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) Digital interaction either emboldens or silences, often. One way to mitigate this is to force a layer of personalization by requiring the use of video chat in classes but this is problematic for a number of potential reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ever tried doing a Google Hangout with more than six people? It can be unbearable. Doing a video-chat meeting in a class with 400 students is both technically and practically impossible. (While Hangouts On Air is an option it removes the two-way communication that the video chat is trying to accomplish in the first place.) Remember, I&amp;rsquo;m specifically talking about video conferences where all users are simultaneously using video. Hangouts is limited to 25 people, Skype is limited to 10 in the free version (though Microsoft suggests 5 for the optimum experience). Zoom&amp;rsquo;s limit is 50 but I&amp;rsquo;d be curious to see just how noisy that can get. Even Slack limits video calls to 15 people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While online programs provide education access to students that may live in extreme rural areas that often comes with bandwidth limitations. This is also something to consider when having students create or download large files. Believe it or not, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailydot.com/debug/dvd-rental-windows-3-aol-2017/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some folks still use dial-up&lt;/a&gt; (through no fault of their own). But broadband as a human right s something I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about before so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it at that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another draw of fully online programs is access to education for &lt;a href=&#34;https://themighty.com/2016/07/taking-classes-online-because-of-social-anxiety/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;those with severe anxiety or socialization hurdles&lt;/a&gt;. In my experience, such students often product superior academic work but stumble when required to speak aloud or join video chats in a classroom setting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time differences for synchronous video classes is also a hurdle. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a class before that included students from 5 different time zones and every hemisphere. Even right now one of the instructors in our program is teaching from the other side of the planet, making a usual 6pm class in Arizona a 3am class in Belgium. Complicate this with students actively stationed in the military, moving from location to location (on top of their network connectivity restrictions) and you&amp;rsquo;ve got a recipe for a grab bag of different learner experiences while maintaining the same expectations of work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In no way do I wish what I&amp;rsquo;m saying here to be construed as derision or disappointment about the online teaching experience. Quite the opposite: it&amp;rsquo;s thrilling, enjoyable, and life-changing for many students (as well as many instructors, myself included). I simply want to point out some aspects about fully online programs that I believe we should not simply accept as shortcomings but begin to actively address. One way I&amp;rsquo;ve been inching toward shoring up the social presence in my classes, program, and campus is the use of Slack to provide everyone&amp;ndash;students, instructors, administrators, the whole shebang&amp;ndash;with a common platform and location to communicate and virtually exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about you? Do you teach or study in a fully online program? What do you think about the lack of physical social interaction? &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ryanstraight&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tweet at me&lt;/a&gt; and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:HAHAHUGOSHORTCOD&#34;&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/rtrn6-cKqkM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:HAHAHUGOSHORTCOD&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
