<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>squad goals network on ryan straight</title>
    <link>https://ryanstraight.com/tags/squad-goals-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in squad goals network on ryan straight</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ryanstraight.com/tags/squad-goals-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>October Squad Ghouls Network Take-Over: Postmortem</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/11/01/october-squad-ghouls-network-take-over-postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/11/01/october-squad-ghouls-network-take-over-postmortem/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as scary as I thought it would be. It was also quieter than I&amp;rsquo;d expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the month of October I was tasked with running the social media for the Squad Goals Network, a collective of pure academic and collaborative brilliance, of which I am honored to be a part. And you know what? I had a pretty good time. That said, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My basic theme for the month was &lt;em&gt;fear&lt;/em&gt;. Partly because it encompassed Halloween and partly because I believe doing things that scare you is an integral part of growing as a fully-realized person. Speaking of which, over the month I came to realize a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;revelation-1-anticipation-is-always-scarier-than-immersion&#34;&gt;Revelation #1: Anticipation is always scarier than immersion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about something is always going to be more terrifying than actually being in the situation. I kept thinking, &amp;ldquo;Is it going to be good enough?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Will I make a fool of myself?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;What if I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to say?&amp;rdquo; Upon reflection, that last one was never a real concern; the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; concern was &amp;ldquo;What if I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; to say?&amp;rdquo; But here&amp;rsquo;s the point: there was never any expectation that the things I posted or wrote would all need to be meticulously crafted, thoughtful, brilliant nuggets of wisdom. If you spend all your time crafting you never actually produce anything, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;revelation-2-i-m-an-amplifier-not-a-bullhorn&#34;&gt;Revelation #2: I&amp;rsquo;m an amplifier, not a bullhorn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some people&amp;mdash;my takeover predecessor Angela and successor Terry, just to name two&amp;mdash;who are fantastic at creating and shouting amazing things. They make connections with new people incredibly easily and actively seek out those connections. I, on the other hand, found myself being more of an amplifier for other people. In terms of Twitter, it manifested in many, many retweets but very few unique, composed tweets. There&amp;rsquo;s no right or wrong way to do this, of course. Each person has their own style and priorities. Still, if I had to choose which I find more useful&amp;hellip; it isn&amp;rsquo;t my version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;revelation-3-a-month-is-no-time-at-all&#34;&gt;Revelation #3: A month is &lt;strong&gt;no time at all&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, wow, did that go quickly. Though it&amp;rsquo;s probably compounded by my birthday being at the end of October and I was eager to have that over and done with. (Thirty seven is such a low-priority age, I feel.) Now that it&amp;rsquo;s November and I can get back into my regular routine it&amp;rsquo;s suddenly conference season and the holidays. There&amp;rsquo;s never enough time for &lt;em&gt;any of it&lt;/em&gt;. Life, I mean. Never.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thank you for putting up with me behind the wheel for a month. I&amp;rsquo;ll still be amplifying the voices of brilliance I&amp;rsquo;m surrounded by in this group and expect those that come after me to do even better (which, to be honest, ain&amp;rsquo;t hard).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: The Harshest Mirror</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/16/9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/16/9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost Halloween. Let&amp;rsquo;s do something scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection is hard. It can be scary. Not for lack of content but for the what it means to potentially confront your shortcomings. Yes, the goal is to improve but to do that you must admit where you are lacking. Of course, we can couch this in platitudes like, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; at it, just that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s an area for growth.&amp;rdquo; And this is most likely true. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the fact that you still have to admit that first part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I think, is fairly typical in higher education, especially for faculty whose entire &lt;em&gt;raison d&amp;rsquo;être&lt;/em&gt; is centered around expertise. It can feel like admitting one needs improvement can be to admit one has failed in some capacity. We all make mistakes, no doubt. We all have more to learn, of course. But it&amp;rsquo;s easier to do that in solitude, safer to make self-reflections private and not do what feels like laying bare your faults and shortcomings in public. Perhaps we all want to be the duck, legs paddling frantically under the water, but looking calm and collected on the surface. I know I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written on imposter syndrome and becoming (or at least playing at being) a public intellectual and thinker. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it comes easily and naturally to most people. For those for whom it does, it seems so &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt;. They seem fearless and display the bright colors of poisonous animals that tells you, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m making myself vunerable to help others; attack at your own peril because you will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; like the outcome.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s something to which to aspire, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I &lt;strong&gt;wish&lt;/strong&gt; I had that sort of strength and fearlessness. As it happens&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t. At least, not yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to be able to say, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; when a student asked a really fantastic or insightful question that I felt like I &lt;em&gt;should&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/em&gt; been able to answer. Perhaps I did know the answer but couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall it at the moment. Perhaps I understood the questions wrong. Perhaps it was just something I flat-out did not know. Of course, we all do the redirect and say something like, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a great question. How about we all do some research and see what we come up with?&amp;rdquo; That is the goal, after all: to get learners to become self-directed. Still, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a great question&amp;rdquo; is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the same as specifically saying, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m still somewhat afraid of that. Remember, there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between being simply ignorant of something and being unprepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is precisely why I chose &amp;ldquo;fear&amp;rdquo; as my SGN topic for the month and why I want to talk about it today: my goal is to overcome that particular fear this year. This month, if I can. Forget the New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution; we need the Halloween Overcoming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: An Introduction and a Plan</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/02/9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/02/9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to join yet another challenge: the &lt;strong&gt;9x9x25 Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;. So, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start off with, let me say that I volunteered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://squadgoalsnetwork.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#SquadGoalsNetwork&lt;/a&gt; for this challenge and take full responsibility for it. That said, I&amp;rsquo;m looking for the entire squad to do the challenge in total, not for each member to do their own 9x9x25 challenge. They can if they want but it&amp;rsquo;s far from necessary. I&amp;rsquo;m hard but I&amp;rsquo;m not cruel, sheesh. The SGN is (and continues to grow into) a collection of incredibly talented and reflective people, so the content produced should be impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s look at what the &lt;strong&gt;9x9x25 Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; is. I was introduced to it via Twitter by our own &lt;a href=&#34;http://squadgoalsnetwork.com/2018/09/19/meet-the-authors-terry-greene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Terry Green&lt;/a&gt;. The challenge is &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://extend-domains.ecampusontario.ca/the-9x9x25-challenge-more-but-not-all-the-details/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;to write about your teaching in 9 posts, over 9 weeks, with a minimum of 25 sentences per post&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first reflection, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth talking a bit about the details of my position: I teach entirely online at both the undergraduate and graduate levels at a very large Research-1 institution, and, while I&amp;rsquo;m at a giant R1, I&amp;rsquo;m what&amp;rsquo;s considered &amp;ldquo;career-track&amp;rdquo; faculty, which is to say I&amp;rsquo;m not tenure-track. My contract consists entirely of teaching and service requirements with no research expected (though, obviously, I still do it, which is the topic for another day). My normal schedule is 80% teaching (so 4 classes per semester, each counting as 20% of my time) and 20% service. This is pretty standard at our institution for career-track faculty, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching entirely online&amp;mdash;and I mean entirely, not just hybrid or having an online section; the entire program is constructed and billed as being online&amp;mdash;makes for an interesting cocktail of convenience, agility, and distance, for both good and bad. We can collaborate in our pajamas, we can make changes and implement them at moment&amp;rsquo;s notice, and reach students that couldn&amp;rsquo;t physically reach us otherwise. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty phenomenal in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can get lonely, though. I go to great pains to build community with my students, within the program, and interdisciplinarily across the college and campus, but at the end of the day I&amp;rsquo;m still sitting in my home office, hitting keys to communicate. Sure, video conferencing has gotten considerably better over the past few years but, just as there&amp;rsquo;s an experiential difference between paper books and ebooks, it&amp;rsquo;s just not the same as sitting down in physical proximity with someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s this distance that actually caused me to accept the invitation to teach an Honors class on main campus every spring semester. But, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that reflection topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of the 9x9x25 challenge is, in part, to encourage us to be more thoughtful and reflective about our teaching practices. The hope I have is that I will really begin focusing on this next week as that&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;new semester&amp;rdquo; for us (a second 7.5-week session within a larger fall semester) and I can begin with a new class experience. I have a TA (kind of, we call it something different and there are other requirements but it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just say &amp;ldquo;TA&amp;rdquo;) and am looking forward to reflecting on how I orchestrate the inclusion of her knowledge and talent into the class. The class that&amp;rsquo;s beginning is hands-down my most popular class, which makes it &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; easier to be positive about reflections. (When students are excited and happy by default it leaves you with more energy to make improvements rather than feeling like you need to put out fires.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to reading others&amp;rsquo; reflections as the challenge progresses!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2018 SGN Social Media Takeover</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/01/october-2018-sgn-social-media-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/01/october-2018-sgn-social-media-takeover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As such, I wanted to share a little bit about the concept, the process, the expectations, and the theme of the month. The sheer organization, thoughtfulness, and inclusion of last month&amp;rsquo;s takeover by &lt;a href=&#34;http://angelagunder.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angela Gunder&lt;/a&gt; means there are some pretty high standards for this month. That was in part the reason for this month&amp;rsquo;s theme: &lt;strong&gt;fear&lt;/strong&gt;. Fun theme, right? Right? I mean, I&amp;rsquo;ve even got one of the &lt;em&gt;Silent Hill&lt;/em&gt; game soundtracks on while I write this. I&amp;rsquo;m 100% committed to this theme, I&amp;rsquo;m tellin&amp;rsquo; ya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why fear? Simple: we all experience it and we best overcome it with help from our support systems, and what is a network like SGN at its core if not a support system? We share thoughts to clarify them, we collaborate to produce ideas and results that we never could&amp;rsquo;ve achieved on our own (synergy, basically, but that word has been robbed of all impact over the years, I think), and we quite literally just ask each other for help sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;m so glad to have been included in this network of brilliance (constellation, remember?) is that I&amp;rsquo;m usually pretty bad about connecting with people. I&amp;rsquo;m terrible with names, I&amp;rsquo;ll fall off the face of the planet for weeks or months at a time as I obsess with something new, and my memory is almost completely overrun with random facts in place of useful things like details about the people in my life. A group like SGN goes a long way to helping me either deal with, remedy, or overcome those shortfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of overcoming fear is admitting one&amp;rsquo;s shortcomings to begin with. While I often think of and paint myself as a non-standard kind of academic (hence &lt;em&gt;The New Professor&lt;/em&gt;, my podcast), I recognize that I&amp;rsquo;m far from perfect and have many, many realms of improvement I can (and should) venture into. For some, like myself, even admitting that can be scary. It&amp;rsquo;s not like it&amp;rsquo;s a secret; nobody&amp;rsquo;s perfect. It&amp;rsquo;s about acknowledging that imperfect as areas for growth, not permanent and irreparable flaws. I sometimes feel we think of ourselves as marble statues, hoping to put on display the most perfect version of ourselves: polished, impressive, towering. Then when we make mistakes or simply fail at something, that patina of perfection is marred in some way that we just know someone is going to notice and it will permanently alter and diminish the persona we&amp;rsquo;ve so carefully sculpted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I get older and learn more and more than I know less and less about the world, it occurs to me that we&amp;rsquo;re not made of marble at all. We&amp;rsquo;re simply clay. We can be remolded and repaired, improved on and changed. This also makes us vulnerable as the wrong person can come along and take a chunk out of you. That&amp;rsquo;s where having a network, whether it&amp;rsquo;s a personal learning network or a support network comes in (though, as I said, I&amp;rsquo;d venture to say they&amp;rsquo;re often one and the same): not only do your friends and family and colleagues help you repair that damage, whatever it may be, but they help you become a better version of yourself. And that&amp;rsquo;s what we should all be striving for, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s what this month is all about, for me, at least: acknowledging our fears, admitting we all make mistakes and sometimes fail despite our best efforts, and understanding that &lt;em&gt;that&amp;rsquo;s okay&lt;/em&gt;. When students tell me they&amp;rsquo;re anxious about a defense, for example, I always say the same thing: that means you care. Fear can be a great motivator if you let it be, if you can accept it as a hurdle to overcome rather than a door being shut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, I&amp;rsquo;d like you to share with me and the rest of the squad what you&amp;rsquo;re afraid of and, if we can, we can work on it together. Also, I make absolutely no apologies for the massive number of Halloween puns and jokes that I&amp;rsquo;ll be making this month. I&amp;rsquo;m a Halloween baby and it&amp;rsquo;s creeped into the very fabric of my being. So, join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sqdglsntwrk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Squad Ghouls Network&lt;/a&gt; (see?) for a month of acknowledging, admitting, and overcoming your fears.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
