<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflection on ryan straight</title>
    <link>https://ryanstraight.com/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflection on ryan straight</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ryanstraight.com/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Order in Chaos</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/11/02/finding-order-in-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/11/02/finding-order-in-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to say I&amp;rsquo;m the &lt;em&gt;typical&lt;/em&gt; professor (heck, I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenewprofessor.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;an entire podcast devoted to exploring just what the heck that means&lt;/a&gt;) but I certainly do occasionally resemble the clichéd &lt;em&gt;absent-minded professor&lt;/em&gt;. Remember: good thoughts are clear thoughts and that&amp;rsquo;s much harder than it sounds when your job is to think about so much, so often, for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it simply, we have a lot of stuff in our heads. In my experience, one of the most difficult and daunting aspects of working in a primarily intellectual field is nothing more than the organization of thoughts and ideas. We&amp;rsquo;re confronted with new ideas, questions, corrections, updates, improvements, alterations, and retractions nearly every day as we learn more and more about virtually everything. So the question becomes: if we&amp;rsquo;re not superhuman, how do we keep track?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose you could make it your priority to spend the entirety of your time and energy on memorizing the minutiae of everything but, let&amp;rsquo;s face it, we&amp;rsquo;re not all cut out for that kind of perfect recall. I, for one, need to keep notes or I just &lt;em&gt;forget&lt;/em&gt;. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re the same. But then the question becomes: where do you keep them? How do you organize them? How much do you automate and how much do you update? Whether it&amp;rsquo;s your reading notes on one particular scholar&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;ouvre&lt;/em&gt; or a little reminder to add a particular resource to an assignment for a class, we (normally) can&amp;rsquo;t just keep all that in our heads. I know some people, like the prolific Raul Pacheco-Vega, that use physical bucket-style collections (in his case, the &amp;ldquo;Everything Notebook&amp;rdquo;). Others create hundreds or thousands of Google Documents or giant Scrivener projects. The important part is that it works &lt;em&gt;for them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a very, very long time to figure out a system that a) is sustainable, b) I&amp;rsquo;ll actually use, and c) is designed in a way that mirrors (or at least generally reflects) the way my thought processes work. I tried virtually every organizational paradigm out there, from the Evernote-style bucket to physical notebooks (and, I have to say, I&amp;rsquo;m devastated that physical notebooks don&amp;rsquo;t do it for me because I &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; them and own many, many blank ones). What I discovered is, beyond all that, that I love creating systems. What I love less than that is &lt;em&gt;maintaining&lt;/em&gt; them. So, my job became to find a system that I felt like I was creating &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;, something malleable, something always growing and improving, and something within which I could automate the more mundane tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve listened to &lt;a href=&#34;https://thenewprofessor.com/019/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;episode 19 of The New Professor&lt;/a&gt;, you already know what I&amp;rsquo;m going to say next: for me, even though it may sound like a lot of work, the best environment to off-load information and ideas is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.semantic-mediawiki.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Semantic MediaWiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want to know exactly how I do that or what it looks like&amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait on another post. (I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping the wiki for nearly a decade and created a three-part series on how to set one up back in, probably, 2009 but that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; gone.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So watch for those posts. Hopefully they can be of help to you. (Whenever they get here.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: The Harshest Mirror</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/16/9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/16/9x9x25-challenge-the-harshest-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost Halloween. Let&amp;rsquo;s do something scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection is hard. It can be scary. Not for lack of content but for the what it means to potentially confront your shortcomings. Yes, the goal is to improve but to do that you must admit where you are lacking. Of course, we can couch this in platitudes like, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; at it, just that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s an area for growth.&amp;rdquo; And this is most likely true. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the fact that you still have to admit that first part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I think, is fairly typical in higher education, especially for faculty whose entire &lt;em&gt;raison d&amp;rsquo;être&lt;/em&gt; is centered around expertise. It can feel like admitting one needs improvement can be to admit one has failed in some capacity. We all make mistakes, no doubt. We all have more to learn, of course. But it&amp;rsquo;s easier to do that in solitude, safer to make self-reflections private and not do what feels like laying bare your faults and shortcomings in public. Perhaps we all want to be the duck, legs paddling frantically under the water, but looking calm and collected on the surface. I know I do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written on imposter syndrome and becoming (or at least playing at being) a public intellectual and thinker. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it comes easily and naturally to most people. For those for whom it does, it seems so &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt;. They seem fearless and display the bright colors of poisonous animals that tells you, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m making myself vunerable to help others; attack at your own peril because you will &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; like the outcome.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s something to which to aspire, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I &lt;strong&gt;wish&lt;/strong&gt; I had that sort of strength and fearlessness. As it happens&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t. At least, not yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to be able to say, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; when a student asked a really fantastic or insightful question that I felt like I &lt;em&gt;should&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/em&gt; been able to answer. Perhaps I did know the answer but couldn&amp;rsquo;t recall it at the moment. Perhaps I understood the questions wrong. Perhaps it was just something I flat-out did not know. Of course, we all do the redirect and say something like, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a great question. How about we all do some research and see what we come up with?&amp;rdquo; That is the goal, after all: to get learners to become self-directed. Still, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s a great question&amp;rdquo; is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the same as specifically saying, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m still somewhat afraid of that. Remember, there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between being simply ignorant of something and being unprepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is precisely why I chose &amp;ldquo;fear&amp;rdquo; as my SGN topic for the month and why I want to talk about it today: my goal is to overcome that particular fear this year. This month, if I can. Forget the New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution; we need the Halloween Overcoming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9x9x25 Challenge: An Introduction and a Plan</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/02/9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2018/10/02/9x9x25-challenge-an-introduction-and-a-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to join yet another challenge: the &lt;strong&gt;9x9x25 Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;. So, here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start off with, let me say that I volunteered the &lt;a href=&#34;https://squadgoalsnetwork.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;#SquadGoalsNetwork&lt;/a&gt; for this challenge and take full responsibility for it. That said, I&amp;rsquo;m looking for the entire squad to do the challenge in total, not for each member to do their own 9x9x25 challenge. They can if they want but it&amp;rsquo;s far from necessary. I&amp;rsquo;m hard but I&amp;rsquo;m not cruel, sheesh. The SGN is (and continues to grow into) a collection of incredibly talented and reflective people, so the content produced should be impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, let&amp;rsquo;s look at what the &lt;strong&gt;9x9x25 Challenge&lt;/strong&gt; is. I was introduced to it via Twitter by our own &lt;a href=&#34;http://squadgoalsnetwork.com/2018/09/19/meet-the-authors-terry-greene/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Terry Green&lt;/a&gt;. The challenge is &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://extend-domains.ecampusontario.ca/the-9x9x25-challenge-more-but-not-all-the-details/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;to write about your teaching in 9 posts, over 9 weeks, with a minimum of 25 sentences per post&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first reflection, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth talking a bit about the details of my position: I teach entirely online at both the undergraduate and graduate levels at a very large Research-1 institution, and, while I&amp;rsquo;m at a giant R1, I&amp;rsquo;m what&amp;rsquo;s considered &amp;ldquo;career-track&amp;rdquo; faculty, which is to say I&amp;rsquo;m not tenure-track. My contract consists entirely of teaching and service requirements with no research expected (though, obviously, I still do it, which is the topic for another day). My normal schedule is 80% teaching (so 4 classes per semester, each counting as 20% of my time) and 20% service. This is pretty standard at our institution for career-track faculty, I believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching entirely online&amp;mdash;and I mean entirely, not just hybrid or having an online section; the entire program is constructed and billed as being online&amp;mdash;makes for an interesting cocktail of convenience, agility, and distance, for both good and bad. We can collaborate in our pajamas, we can make changes and implement them at moment&amp;rsquo;s notice, and reach students that couldn&amp;rsquo;t physically reach us otherwise. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty phenomenal in that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can get lonely, though. I go to great pains to build community with my students, within the program, and interdisciplinarily across the college and campus, but at the end of the day I&amp;rsquo;m still sitting in my home office, hitting keys to communicate. Sure, video conferencing has gotten considerably better over the past few years but, just as there&amp;rsquo;s an experiential difference between paper books and ebooks, it&amp;rsquo;s just not the same as sitting down in physical proximity with someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s this distance that actually caused me to accept the invitation to teach an Honors class on main campus every spring semester. But, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that reflection topic for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of the 9x9x25 challenge is, in part, to encourage us to be more thoughtful and reflective about our teaching practices. The hope I have is that I will really begin focusing on this next week as that&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;new semester&amp;rdquo; for us (a second 7.5-week session within a larger fall semester) and I can begin with a new class experience. I have a TA (kind of, we call it something different and there are other requirements but it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just say &amp;ldquo;TA&amp;rdquo;) and am looking forward to reflecting on how I orchestrate the inclusion of her knowledge and talent into the class. The class that&amp;rsquo;s beginning is hands-down my most popular class, which makes it &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; easier to be positive about reflections. (When students are excited and happy by default it leaves you with more energy to make improvements rather than feeling like you need to put out fires.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to reading others&amp;rsquo; reflections as the challenge progresses!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Expertise and Being &#39;Out There&#39;</title>
      <link>https://ryanstraight.com/2017/03/01/on-expertise-and-being-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanstraight.com/2017/03/01/on-expertise-and-being-out-there/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was reading Katie Linder&amp;rsquo;s Medium essay &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@katie__linder/when-do-you-call-yourself-an-expert-f273b17a02e9#.jpz9ksg5k&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;When Do You Call Yourself an Expert&lt;/a&gt; on the same day that listened to her &lt;a href=&#34;http://ygtpodcast.com/ep23/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Imposter Syndrome&lt;/a&gt; episode on the You&amp;rsquo;ve Got This podcast while getting ready for Faculty Forum. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s a coincidence, honestly. I mean, the timing might be but I&amp;rsquo;m clearly drawn to this topic. So, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write up my own thoughts about it and publish them on the internet because, hey, bravery comes before confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essay reminded me of what I feel like was my first out there moment in which I was also interviewed for a podcast. Hers was for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://teachinginhighered.com/episodes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Teaching in Higher Ed podcast&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bonni208&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bonnie Stachowiak&lt;/a&gt;, while mine was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://immersivelrn.org/resources/the-versatilist-podcast/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Versatilist podcast&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by the wonderfully welcoming Patrick O&amp;rsquo;Shea. Like Katie, I can safely say the experience was enjoyable, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with it, and I&amp;rsquo;m not unhappy with the result. To be fair, I&amp;rsquo;ve never actually even listened to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.podomatic.com/podcasts/versatilist/episodes/2015-10-26T10_27_09-07_00&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;my Versatilist podcast episode&lt;/a&gt; as I a) can&amp;rsquo;t abide the sound of my own voice (an unfortunate state of affairs considering I teach fully online and record myself teaching upwards of 4 times a week), and b) well, precisely what I&amp;rsquo;m getting into with this piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did the Versatilist I had just begun my teaching and had only just recently graduated with my Ph.D, though I was already full-time faculty and was taking over as Program Director while the former PD was on sabbatical. Needless to say, I was a bit out of my depth and unprepared, considering I got so few chances to teach while in graduate school as I was working full time as a trainer for the University&amp;rsquo;s IT department. Regardless, when I was asked to be on the podcast I thought, &amp;lsquo;Sure, why not?&amp;rsquo; Again, bravery before confidence, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did the podcast and I think it went fine. I enjoyed the 45-ish minutes and never really felt like I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was talking about, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t (and to a certain extent still don&amp;rsquo;t) feel like an &lt;em&gt;expert&lt;/em&gt; in any particular field. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I&amp;rsquo;m not working on it but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel comfortable wearing the badge just quite yet. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s why I was a good fit for the Versatilist: Jack of all trades and master of none? Who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pixabay.com/en/mike-sound-system-podcast-1737612/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mic.png&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; alt=&#34;By Mindthaw via Pixabay.&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
One scary thing for me was the idea that there would now be a record of me rambling on about this and that, from my doctoral research to my experience teaching as new faculty, but that anyone could access it at any time and &lt;em&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be there to respond&lt;/em&gt;. If I tweet something or say something in class there&amp;rsquo;s an avenue for discussion, for dialog, be it synchronous or asynchronous. Being a guest on a podcast is, obviously, being interviewed and having that interview published: it&amp;rsquo;s out there and that sole fact invites scrutiny. (Going on another this week, coincidentally.) So maybe it&amp;rsquo;s more a fear of making a mistake and being caught out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, one point I wanted to make in the podcast (and why we&amp;rsquo;ve taken this winding path) was that I think I&amp;rsquo;ve always been hungry for something different. I&amp;rsquo;m a neophile, a fan of novelty with a great love of the new-and-improved. That is to say, I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for more&amp;hellip; more information, more methods, more theories, more examples, more tools. More, more, more. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that if I ever find myself settling comfortably into the &lt;em&gt;expert&lt;/em&gt; chair then that part of me could disappear, as if expertise were a destination and not a journey (to get all cat-hanging-from-a-ledge-motivational-poster for a minute). I don&amp;rsquo;t want that to happen. Satisfaction is having one foot in the grave or some such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it would help new graduates or junior faculty to see that others at the same career point are also in the same boat, confidence- or bravery-wise. It&amp;rsquo;s a long road and not one that has any particular sign posts or even a decent map. We have to make our own ways, sometimes even cut our own paths&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Did-you-know-you&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Did-you-know-you&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Maybe we get lucky enough to find a mentor that has an idea about the ditches and bumps, but that&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee. Navigating all this is part of the process and, frankly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s good for us. Maybe not &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;; maybe &lt;strong&gt;necessary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, for now I think I&amp;rsquo;m most comfortable claiming that I&amp;rsquo;m on a constant path toward expertise. Maybe when I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve finally claimed the prize I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know. Maybe, when I&amp;rsquo;m like Katie and have two-almost-three books under my belt, I&amp;rsquo;ll claim it. Until then, hi-ho, hi-ho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Did-you-know-you&#34;&gt;Did you know you can buy machetes at Home Depot? They&amp;rsquo;re with the gardening tools. That blew my mind. Not sure where I thought they were sold before I discovered this. Not sure I&amp;rsquo;d ever thought about where they&amp;rsquo;re sold before then. It just struck me as odd. &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Did-you-know-you&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
