<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>growth on ryan straight</title>
    <link>/tags/growth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in growth on ryan straight</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/growth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Expertise and Being &#39;Out There&#39;</title>
      <link>/2017/03/01/on-expertise-and-being-out-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/01/on-expertise-and-being-out-there/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I was reading Katie Linder’s Medium essay &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@katie__linder/when-do-you-call-yourself-an-expert-f273b17a02e9#.jpz9ksg5k&#34;&gt;When Do You Call Yourself an Expert&lt;/a&gt; on the same day that listened to her &lt;a href=&#34;http://ygtpodcast.com/ep23/&#34;&gt;Imposter Syndrome&lt;/a&gt; episode on the You’ve Got This podcast while getting ready for Faculty Forum. I don’t think that’s a coincidence, honestly. I mean, the timing might be but I’m clearly drawn to this topic. So, I thought I’d write up my own thoughts about it and publish them on the internet because, hey, bravery comes before confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The essay reminded me of what I feel like was my first out there moment in which I was also interviewed for a podcast. Hers was for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://teachinginhighered.com/episodes/&#34;&gt;Teaching in Higher Ed podcast&lt;/a&gt; hosted by the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bonni208&#34;&gt;Bonnie Stachowiak&lt;/a&gt;, while mine was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://immersivelrn.org/resources/the-versatilist-podcast/&#34;&gt;Versatilist podcast&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by the wonderfully welcoming Patrick O’Shea. Like Katie, I can safely say the experience was enjoyable, there’s nothing wrong with it, and I’m not unhappy with the result. To be fair, I’ve never actually even listened to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.podomatic.com/podcasts/versatilist/episodes/2015-10-26T10_27_09-07_00&#34;&gt;my Versatilist podcast episode&lt;/a&gt; as I a) can’t abide the sound of my own voice (an unfortunate state of affairs considering I teach fully online and record myself teaching upwards of 4 times a week), and b) well, precisely what I’m getting into with this piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I did the Versatilist I had just begun my teaching and had only just recently graduated with my Ph.D, though I was already full-time faculty and was taking over as Program Director while the former PD was on sabbatical. Needless to say, I was a bit out of my depth and unprepared, considering I got so few chances to teach while in graduate school as I was working full time as a trainer for the University’s IT department. Regardless, when I was asked to be on the podcast I thought, ‘Sure, why not?’ Again, bravery before confidence, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did the podcast and I think it went fine. I enjoyed the 45-ish minutes and never really felt like I didn’t know what I was talking about, but I didn’t (and to a certain extent still don’t) feel like an &lt;em&gt;expert&lt;/em&gt; in any particular field. That’s not to say I’m not working on it but I don’t feel comfortable wearing the badge just quite yet. Maybe that’s why I was a good fit for the Versatilist: Jack of all trades and master of none? Who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pixabay.com/en/mike-sound-system-podcast-1737612/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mic.png&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; alt=&#34;By Mindthaw via Pixabay.&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
One scary thing for me was the idea that there would now be a record of me rambling on about this and that, from my doctoral research to my experience teaching as new faculty, but that anyone could access it at any time and &lt;em&gt;I couldn’t be there to respond&lt;/em&gt;. If I tweet something or say something in class there’s an avenue for discussion, for dialog, be it synchronous or asynchronous. Being a guest on a podcast is, obviously, being interviewed and having that interview published: it’s out there and that sole fact invites scrutiny. (Going on another this week, coincidentally.) So maybe it’s more a fear of making a mistake and being caught out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, one point I wanted to make in the podcast (and why we’ve taken this winding path) was that I think I’ve always been hungry for something different. I’m a neophile, a fan of novelty with a great love of the new-and-improved. That is to say, I’m always looking for more… more information, more methods, more theories, more examples, more tools. More, more, more. I’m afraid that if I ever find myself settling comfortably into the &lt;em&gt;expert&lt;/em&gt; chair then that part of me could disappear, as if expertise were a destination and not a journey (to get all cat-hanging-from-a-ledge-motivational-poster for a minute). I don’t want that to happen. Satisfaction is having one foot in the grave or some such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it would help new graduates or junior faculty to see that others at the same career point are also in the same boat, confidence- or bravery-wise. It’s a long road and not one that has any particular sign posts or even a decent map. We have to make our own ways, sometimes even cut our own paths&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe we get lucky enough to find a mentor that has an idea about the ditches and bumps, but that’s no guarantee. Navigating all this is part of the process and, frankly, I think it’s good for us. Maybe not &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt;; maybe &lt;strong&gt;necessary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, for now I think I’m most comfortable claiming that I’m on a constant path toward expertise. Maybe when I feel like I’ve finally claimed the prize I’ll let you know. Maybe, when I’m like Katie and have two-almost-three books under my belt, I’ll claim it. Until then, hi-ho, hi-ho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Did you know you can buy machetes at Home Depot? They’re with the gardening tools. That blew my mind. Not sure where I thought they were sold before I discovered this. Not sure I’d ever thought about where they’re sold before then. It just struck me as odd.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-back&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
